Guide to the Summer Theater at Duke records, 1925-1984
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Summer Theater at Duke records 1925-1984
University Archives, Duke University
Duke University. Summer Theater at Duke.
0.5 Linear Feet 250 Items
The Summer Theater program at Duke was created in 1972; its founding members included English Professor John Clum and Duke Players president Richard E. Cytowic.
The collection includes programs, playbills, newspaper clippings, schedules, ticket order forms, posters, advertisements, flyers, pamphlets, box office reports, reviews, and notes related to the Summer Theater program. Materials range in date from 1925-1984, bulk dates 1973-1984.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Summer Theater at Duke records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1977-1980.
Historical Note
The Summer Theater program at Duke was created in 1972; its founding members included English Professor John Clum and Duke Players president Richard E. Cytowic. Beginning in 1973, the company put on regular performances throughout the summer, to much critical acclaim.
Collection Overview
The collection includes programs, playbills, newspaper clippings, schedules, ticket order forms, posters, advertisements, flyers, pamphlets, box office reports, reviews, and notes related to the Summer Theater program. Other than one playbill from 1925, the materials date between 1973 and 1984. The 1925 playbill is from a presentation of Sheridan's "A School for Scandal," by the Coffer-Millar Players, performed for students of the Summer School at Duke University.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Community theater -- North Carolina -- Durham.
Duke University. Summer Theater at Duke.
Theater.
Related Material
Reynolds Price Papers, 1927-2006 and undated, bulk 1956-2006
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Trinity College of Arts and Sciences, Office of the Dean records, 1934-2003
University Archives, Duke University.
A long and happy life / by John Clum
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Contents of Collection
- Container List, 1 Box
  - Summer Theater at Duke Records, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Summer Theater at Duke, 1973-1984
  - Summer Theater at Duke- Printed Matter, 1973-1983
  - Clippings, 1973-1984
  - Summer Theater at Duke- Box Office Reports, 1978
  - "Duke Summer Opera Workshop", 1980-1981
  - Reviews, Summer 1978
  - Summer Theater Info, 1979
  - Reviews, Summer 1979
  - Summer 1982, Publicity Advertisements